# Akhator Osakhogba



#### Contact

# **City:** Abuja

#### Phone:

+234 703 985 4258

#### **Email:**

aosakhogba@gmail.com

#### Website:

<u>Personal Website</u> Linkedin Profile

## Languages

**English** 

### Summary

I am Akhator Osakhogba, alias Osa, specializing in front end development that brings front- and back-end design to promote organization-specific website presence with working knowloegde of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL and Wordpress to generate custom website design. Detail-oriented approach to maintaining website responsiveness, effectiveness and security. Hardworking and passionate with strong organizational skills and ready to learn new things to help team achieve company goals.

#### **Skills**

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Responsive design
- CMS management
- PHP
- MySQL
- Service-focused

## Experience

### Freelance Web Developer- 2018 to Current

 Worked on different web development projects for businesses over the years.

# System Support Analyst Intern- 03/2017 to 12/2017 Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC), Abuja

- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Ordered, maintained and distributed supplies and inventory.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Devoted special emphasis to punctuality and worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately.
- Engaged in daily operations to ensure high levels of productivity.

# **Software Developer Intern**- 03/2017 to 12/2017 **Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC)**, Abuja

 Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easy-to-use versions.

- Assisted web presence planning, implementing changes and integrating requested elements to streamline business operations.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Converted graphic designs to usable web images using Adobe Photo Shop.
- Indulged back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science: **Computer Science** - 2021

Ambrose Alli University, Ekpoma